# Oanh Do

## **Database Developer**

Salt Lake, UT - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Oanh-Do/cb78069f94fafe55

14 years of working experience in software development, especially in Database, Reports and ETL

2 years of experience in Project management. Involve in defining process/template, planning, controlling progress, coordinating development and QA teams, offshore and onshore teams

2 years of onsite (US) experience

Expertise in DBMS, Data warehouses and Business Intelligence suites: Microsoft SQL, Informatica, Pentaho, MySQL

Experienced in Agile and RUP methodologies

Major clients: Kiewit, Micros, Sheridan Healthcare Inc, Zurich UK, Medplus, Plexis

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Associate Engineering Manager/Database developer

CSC Vietnam - Thành phố Hồ Chí Minh - May 2004 to April 2015

Vietnam (May 2004 to Apr 2015)

- Managed Micros offshore development team using Agile Jira. The team included 20 members and divided into three sub teams. Each team is responsible for developing and maintaining a specific system of Micros hospitality platform. My responsibilities were defining working process for each sub team, supporting team with difficult database issues, creating project plan, tracking daily activities/progress and reporting to CSC and Micros' managers.
- Worked onsite at Kiewit headquarter as an onshore coordinator. My main tasks were getting works from client and transfer to offshore team, working closely with offshore manager to ensure the team understand client's expectation and deliver products in time.
- Worked onsite at Kiewit headquarter as an DB/Reporting developer. Maintained and enhanced the most complex report of Kiewit, Cost Report, using SQL server 2008 and SSRS
- Technical lead of Zurich UK team. We created a single data store in SQL Server 2008, which takes inputs from multiple sources globally, then used Informatica to transform the data into a standard data format and produces a single view of risk. I involved in requirement analysis, technical designs, issue management and implementing Informatica ETL workflows
- Technical lead of Peregrine Network team. The team built a data warehouse system using MySQL and used Pentaho to transfer data to data warehouse and develop a report system (including financial and operational reports). I involved in requirement analysis, designing and implementing ETL packages and reports, supporting team with DB issues.
- Database/Report developer in Sheridan Healthcare SMART project. The project was to build a full Revenue Cycle Management System for a healthcare provider. My responsibilities included requirement analysis with onshore SMEs, database design, implementing SQL stored procedures, functions, SSRS reports, deployment and performing demo/presentation to end users

- Database/Report developer in projects: Plexis Claim Processing, MedPlus Healthcare Client portal, Third Millennium Inc RCMS Involved in many database tasks:
- o Worked at client site as a Database/report developer.
- o Developed database design document.
- o Developed reports using SSRS, Crystal report
- o Converted databases: from MS SQL 6.5 to MS SQL 8.0, from MS SQL to Oracle
- o Wrote stored-procedures, functions, database scripts and supported client's developers with database tasks
- o Optimized SQL queries
- o Backup/restore database,
- o Prepared database and scripts for builds, created sample data
- .NET developers in various projects which developed desktop/web applications for CSC's clients. My tasks involved mostly in coding and unit testing with C#, VB.NET, MSSQL Server.

## .NET/Database developer

Minh Tue Ltd - Thành phố Hồ Chí Minh - 2002 to May 2004

Developed an accounting system for small and medium size companies in Vietnam. I was responsible for key components in that system such as Account Receivable, Inventory and Reporting.

Technologies used: VB.NET, Crystal report, SQL 2000

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Computer Science**

University of Natural Sciences September 2001

#### **SKILLS**

SQL Server 2008, Reporting Services, MySQL,Crystal Report, Pentaho (ETL and Reporting), Informatica (ETL), MS project, Visio, JIRA, HPQC, SVN

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

### Soft skills:

- Team leadership, coaching, negotiation, people management
- Good operational, organizational and planning skills
- Good communication
- Enthusiasm and have ability to work under high pressure